Guide to the Jewish Labor Committee Records, Part I WAG.025.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: Rescue and Relief
  - Subseries IV:B: Relief
    - Sub Subseries IV:B:1: General
      - Correspondence: General, 1946-1947 (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Czechoslovakia, 1936-1938 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Dachau Lists: Orders to Purchase, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Dominican Republic, 1946-1947 (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - Employment for Refugees, 1943-1946 (Box 48, Folder 7)
      - Employment for Refugees, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 8)
      - Employment: JLC, 1941-1946 (Box 48, Folder 9)
      - England, 1945-1947 (Box 48, Folder 10)
      - Federation for Polish Jews, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 11)
      - France, 1942-1945 (Box 48, Folder 12)
      - France, 1946-1947 (Box 48, Folder 13)
      - France: Refugees in Southern France, [1940] (Box 48, Folder 14)
      - Free Voice of Labor, 1942 (Box 48, Folder 15)
      - Friends of Vilna, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 16)
      - German Exiles, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 16A)
      - German-Jewish Children's Aid, 1937 (Box 48, Folder 17)
      - Germany, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 18)
      - Germany (Nathan Gierowitz), 1947 (Box 48, Folder 19)
      - Germany (Bella Meiksin), 1947 (Box 48, Folder 20)
      - Goldman, Paul L., 1947 (Box 48, Folder 20A)
      - Goldman-Wolpert European Trip, 1945 (Box 48, Folder 21)
      - Hashomer Hatzair, 1945-1947 (Box 48, Folder 22)
      - HIAS, 1941 (Box 48, Folder 23)
        Reel#: 143
      - HIAS, 1942-1944 (Box 48, Folder 24)
      - HIAS, 1945 (Box 48, Folder 25)
      - HIAS, Jan 1946-May 1946 (Box 48, Folder 26)
      - HIAS, Jun 1946-Jul 1946 (Box 48, Folder 27)
      - HIAS, Aug 1946-Dec 1946 (Box 48, Folder 28)
      - HIAS, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 29)
      - Housing, 1946-1947 (Box 48, Folder 30)
      - Hungarian Press, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 31)
      - Immigration General, 1940-1942 (Box 48, Folder 32)
      - Immigration General, 1943-1946 (Box 48, Folder 33)
      - Immigration General, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 34)
    - Sub Subseries IV:B:2: Immigration: Individual Files (arranged alphabetically)
      - Alperin, Rose, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 35)
      - Alter, David M., 1946-1947 (Box 48, Folder 36)
      - Apelbaum, Israel, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 37)
      - Bagno, L., 1947 (Box 48, Folder 38)
      - Barlaz, George, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 39)
      - Becker, Levi, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 40)
      - Boruth, Michael, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 41)
      - Bremer, David, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 42)
      - Brettler, Josef, 1946-1947 (Box 48, Folder 43)
      - Briliant, S., 1947 (Box 48, Folder 44)
      - Bronstein de Castillo, Victoria, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 45)
      - Brown, Sylvia, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 46)
      - Brumberg, Joseph, 1945-1947 (Box 48, Folder 47)
      - Chabotsky, Oscar, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 48)
      - Ciechanowsky, Samuel, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 49)
      - Cook, A.F., 1946 (Box 48, Folder 50)
      - Chryzman, Ilja, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 51)
      - Ehrlich, Szoszka, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 52)
      - Eisenstark, Szmul, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 53)
      - Fabry, Paul and Gabriella, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 54)
      - Falk, Ignacy, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 55)
      - Faltz, H., 1946-1947 (Box 48, Folder 56)
      - Finkelstein, L.L., 1947-1948 (Box 48, Folder 57)
      - Garfinkel, B., 1946 (Box 48, Folder 58)
      - Gershner, Emanuel, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 59)
      - Goldberg, L., 1947 (Box 48, Folder 60)
      - Goldstein, Jan, 1946-1949 (Box 48, Folder 61)
        Reel#: 144
      - Greisdorf, David, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 62)
      - Grigorieff, H., 1947 (Box 48, Folder 63)
      - Grossbard, Hersz Naftali, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 64)
      - Gutgold, Joseph, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 65)
      - Hamburg, Shepsel, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 66)
      - Heser, Esther, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 67)
      - Hirschfeld, Hans Emil, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 68)
      - Hoffman, Sarah, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 69)
      - Iedlin, Pessa, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 70)
      - Jachimowicz, Binem, 1947-1948 (Box 48, Folder 71)
      - Keller, Chana, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 72)
      - Kertesz, I., 1946-1947 (Box 48, Folder 73)
      - Kleinman, Louis, 1946-1947 (Box 48, Folder 74)
      - Klingsberg, Bernard, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 75)
      - Kursky, Maximillian Blumin, 1946-1947 (Box 48, Folder 76)
      - Lifszyc, Joseph and Helena, 1945-1948 (Box 48, Folder 77)
      - Lodyjensky, Jean and Mary, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 78)
      - Mlotek, Yosl, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 79)
      - Osewicki, Abram, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 80)
      - Patt, Emanuel, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 81)
      - Pentelka, Halina, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 82)
      - Piltchik, M., 1947 (Box 48, Folder 83)
      - Pomeranc, Dora, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 84)
      - Pistiner, Rosa, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 85)
      - Rothman, Sarah, 1946-1948 (Box 48, Folder 86)
      - Schorsch, Alice, 1946-1947 (Box 48, Folder 87)
      - Schwartz, Bela, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 88)
      - Shatskin, J., 1947 (Box 48, Folder 89)
      - Shneider, 1946-1947 (Box 48, Folder 90)
      - Spiro, Mayer, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 91)
      - Stein, Chatzkel, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 92)
      - Stein, Fred, 1941-1947 (Box 48, Folder 93)
      - Steier, George, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 94)
      - Sudarsky, S., 1946-1947 (Box 48, Folder 95)
      - Szafran, Ethel, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 96)
      - Tabachnik, H., 1947 (Box 48, Folder 97)
      - Ticker, Sam, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 98)
      - Wasser, Mark, 1947-1948 (Box 48, Folder 99)
      - Weisz, Esther, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 100)
      - Wygodzki, Daniel, [1947] (Box 48, Folder 101)
      - Intergovernmental Committee on Refugees, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 102)
      - International Refugee Organization, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - International Relief Organization, 1937 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - International Rescue and Relief Committee, 1943-1945 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - International Rescue and Relief Committee, Jan 1946-Jun 1946 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - International Rescue and Relief Committee, Jul 1946-Dec 1946 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - International Rescue andRelief Committee, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - International Workers Order, 1942 (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - Italy, 1945 (Box 49, Folder 8)
      - Jewish Labor Bund, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - Jewish National Workers' Alliance, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 10)
      - Jewish Writers Fund, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 11)
      - Joint Emergency Committee for European Jewish Affairs, 1943 (Box 49, Folder 12)
      - Landsmanshaft (Lodz), 1947-1949 (Box 49, Folder 13)
      - Landsmanshaft (Wilno), 1946-1947 (Box 49, Folder 14)
      - Landsmanshaft (Zloczow), 1947 (Box 49, Folder 15)
      - Landsmanshaftn: General, 1937 (Box 49, Folder 16)
      - Landsmanshaftn: General, 1944-1945 (Box 49, Folder 17)
      - Landsmanshaftn: General, 1946 (Box 49, Folder 18)
      - Landsmanshaftn: General, Jan 1947-Dec 1947 (Box 49, Folder 19)
        Reel#: 145
      - Landsmanshaftn: General, Aug 1947-Dec 1947 (Box 49, Folder 20)
      - Landsmanshaftn (Search for Relatives), Jan 1947-Jun 1947 (Box 49, Folder 21)
      - Latvia, 1937 (Box 49, Folder 22)
      - Left Poale Zion, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 23)
      - Mexico, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 24)
      - Netherlands, 1942 (Box 49, Folder 25)
      - Norway, 1946 (Box 49, Folder 26)
      - Norway, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 27)
      - ORT, 1937, 1942 (Box 49, Folder 28)
      - ORT, 1944 (Box 49, Folder 29)
      - ORT, 1945 (Box 49, Folder 30)
      - ORT, 1946 (Box 49, Folder 31)
      - ORT, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 32)
      - OSE, 1942, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 33)
      - Palestine, 1936, 1945-1947 (Box 49, Folder 34)
      - Poland, Jan 1937-Jun 1937 (Box 49, Folder 35)
      - Poland, Jul 1937-Dec 1937 (Box 49, Folder 36)
      - Poland, Jan 1938-Jun 1938 (Box 49, Folder 37)
        Reel#: 146
      - Poland, Jul 1938-Dec 1938 (Box 49, Folder 38)
      - Poland, 1939 (Box 49, Folder 39)
      - Poland, 1940, 1944 (Box 49, Folder 40)
      - Poland, 1945-1947 (Box 49, Folder 41)
      - Polish-American Press, 1945-1947 (Box 49, Folder 42)
      - Polish Rescuers, 1946-1947 (Box 49, Folder 43)
      - Relative Search, 1943-1944 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - Relative Search, 1945 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - Relative Search, 1946, undated (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Relative Search, Jan 1946-Jun 1946 (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - Relative Search, Jul 1946-Dec 1946 (Box 50, Folder 5)
        Reel#: 147
      - Relative Search, 1947 (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - Relative Search: A, 1946 (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - Relative Search: A, 1947 (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - Relative Search: B, 1946 (Box 50, Folder 9)
      - Relative Search: B, Jan 1947-Jul 1947 (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - Relative Search: B, Jul 1947-Dec 1947 (Box 50, Folder 11)
      - Relative Search: C, 1946 (Box 50, Folder 12)
      - Relative Search: C, 1947 (Box 50, Folder 13)
      - Relative Search: D, 1946 (Box 50, Folder 14)
      - Relative Search: D, 1947 (Box 50, Folder 15)
        Reel#: 148
      - Relative Search: E, 1945 (Box 50, Folder 16)
      - Relative Search: E, 1946 (Box 50, Folder 17)
      - Relative Search: E, 1947 (Box 50, Folder 18)
      - Relative Search: F, 1946 (Box 50, Folder 19)
      - Relative Search: F, 1947 (Box 50, Folder 20)
      - Relative Search: G, 1945 (Box 50, Folder 21)
      - Relative Search: G, 1946 (Box 50, Folder 22)
      - Relative Search: G, Jan 1947-Aug 1947 (Box 50, Folder 23)
      - Relative Search: G, Jul 1947-Dec 1947 (Box 50, Folder 24)
      - Relative Search: H, 1946 (Box 50, Folder 25)
      - Relative Search: H, 1947 (Box 50, Folder 26)
      - Relative Search: I, 1946 (Box 50, Folder 27)
        Reel#: 149
      - Relative Search: I, 1947 (Box 50, Folder 28)
      - Relative Search: J, 1946 (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Relative Search: J, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - Relative Search: K, 1946 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Relative Search: K, Jan 1947-Jun 1947 (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - Relative Search: K, Jul 1947-Dec 1947 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - Relative Search: L, 1945 (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Relative Search: L, 1946 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - Relative Search: L, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 8)
      - Relative Search: M, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 9)
      - Relative Search: N, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 10)
      - Relative Search: O, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 11)
      - Relative Search: P, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 12)
        Reel#: 150
      - Relative Search: R, 1946 (Box 51, Folder 13)
      - Relative Search: R, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 14)
      - Relative Search: S, Jan 1946-May 1946 (Box 51, Folder 15)
      - Relative Search: S, Jun 1946-Dec 1946 (Box 51, Folder 16)
      - Relative Search: S, Jan 1947-Jun 1947 (Box 51, Folder 17)
      - Relative Search: S, Jul 1947-Sep 1947 (Box 51, Folder 18)
      - Relative Search: S, Oct 1947-Dec 1947 (Box 51, Folder 19)
      - Relative Search: T, 1946 (Box 51, Folder 20)
        Reel#: 151
      - Relative Search: T, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 21)
      - Relative Search: U, 1946 (Box 51, Folder 22)
      - Relative Search: V, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 23)
      - Relative Search: W, 1946 (Box 51, Folder 24)
      - Relative Search: W, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 25)
      - Relative Search: Y, 1946 (Box 51, Folder 26)
      - Relative Search: Y, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 27)
      - Relative Search: Z, 1946 (Box 51, Folder 28)
      - Relative Search: Z, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 29)
      - Relative Search: Lists, 1945 (Box 51, Folder 30)
      - Relative Search: Lists, 1946 (Box 51, Folder 31)
      - Relative Search: Lists, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 32)
      - Relative Search: Radio, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 33)
      - Relatives Found, 1945 (Box 51, Folder 34)
      - Roumania, 1938 (Box 51, Folder 35)
      - Roumania, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 36)
      - Roumanian Labor League, 1945, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 37)
      - Russians in America, 1942-1947 (Box 51, Folder 38)
        Reel#: 152
      - Socialist Party/YPSL, 1937 (Box 51, Folder 39)
      - Sweden, Jan 1945-Sep 1945 (Box 51, Folder 40)
      - Sweden, Oct 1945-Dec 1945 (Box 51, Folder 42)
      - Sweden, 1946 (Box 51, Folder 43)
      - Sweden, Jan 1947-Jun 1947 (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Sweden, Jul 1947-Dec 1947 (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Switzerland, 1945-1947 (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Tabachinsky, Benjamin, 1940 (Box 52, Folder 3A)
      - Trotsky, Leon (about), 1946 (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - United Galician Jews of America, 1945-1947 (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - United Nations, 1946-1947 (Box 52, Folder 5A)
      - United Service for New Americans, 1946 (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - United Service for New Americans, 1947 (Box 52, Folder 7)
      - Vaad Hahatzala, 1945-1947 (Box 52, Folder 8)
      - Veterans Fund, 1943 (Box 52, Folder 9)
        Reel#: 153
      - War Refugee Board, 1944-1945 (Box 52, Folder 10)
      - War Relief Control Board, 1944-1945 (Box 52, Folder 11)
      - Wilner Farband: Poland, 1947 (Box 52, Folder 12)
      - Workmen's Circle, Jan 1934-Jun 1934 (Box 52, Folder 13)
      - Workmen's Circle, Jul 1934-Dec 1934 (Box 52, Folder 14)
      - Workmen's Circle, Jan 1935-May 1935 (Box 52, Folder 15)
      - Workmen's Circle, Jun 1935-Dec 1935 (Box 52, Folder 16)
      - Workmen's Circle, 1936 (Box 52, Folder 17)
      - Workmen's Circle, 1937 (Box 52, Folder 18)
      - Workmen's Circle, Jan 1938-Feb 1938 (Box 52, Folder 19)
      - Workmen's Circle, Mar 1938-May 1938 (Box 52, Folder 20)
      - Workmen's Circle, Jun 1938-Jul 1938 (Box 52, Folder 21)
      - Workmen's Circle, Aug 1938-Oct 1938 (Box 52, Folder 22)
      - Workmen's Circle, Nov 1938 (Box 52, Folder 23)
        Reel#: 154
      - Workmen's Circle, Dec 1938 (Box 52, Folder 24)
      - Workmen's Circle, 1939 (Box 52, Folder 25)
      - Workmen's Circle, Jan 1940-Apr 1940 (Box 52, Folder 26)
      - Workmen's Circle, May 1940-Dec 1940 (Box 52, Folder 27)
      - Workmen's Circle: Schools Campaign, 1941 (Box 52, Folder 28)
      - Workmen's Circle, Jan 1941-Feb 1941 (Box 52, Folder 29)
      - Workmen's Circle, Mar 1941-Apr 1941 (Box 52, Folder 30)
      - Workmen's Circle, May 1941-Jun 1941 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - Workmen's Circle, Jul 1941-Aug 1941 (Box 53, Folder 1A)
        Reel#: 155
      - Workmen's Circle, Sep 1941-Oct 1941 (Box 53, Folder 2)
      - Workmen's Circle, Nov 1941-Dec 1941 (Box 53, Folder 3)
      - Workmen's Circle, Jan 1942 (Box 53, Folder 4)
      - Workmen's Circle, Feb 1942 (Box 53, Folder 5)
      - Workmen's Circle, Mar 1942 (Box 53, Folder 6)
      - Workmen's Circle, Apr 1942 (Box 53, Folder 7)
      - Workmen's Circle, May 1942 (Box 53, Folder 8)
      - Workmen's Circle, Jun 1942 (Box 53, Folder 9)
      - Workmen's Circle, Jul 1942-Aug 1942 (Box 53, Folder 10)
      - Workmen's Circle, Sep 1942-Oct 1942 (Box 53, Folder 11)
      - Workmen's Circle, Nov 1942 (Box 53, Folder 12)
      - Workmen's Circle, Dec 1942 (Box 53, Folder 13)
        Reel#: 156
      - Workmen's Circle Division: Minutes, 1942 (Box 53, Folder 14)
      - Workmen's Circle Division: Minutes, 1943 (Box 53, Folder 15)
      - Workmen's Circle Protest Meeting, 1943 (Box 53, Folder 16)
      - Workmen's Circle, 1943 (Box 53, Folder 17)
      - Workmen's Circle: Schools Campaign, 1943-1944 (Box 53, Folder 18)
      - Workmen's Circle, Jan 1944-Feb 1944 (Box 53, Folder 19)
      - Workmen's Circle, Mar 1944-Apr 1944 (Box 53, Folder 20)
      - Workmen's Circle, May 1944-Jun 1944 (Box 53, Folder 21)
      - Workmen's Circle, Jul 1944-Aug 1944 (Box 53, Folder 22)
      - Workmen's Circle, Sep 1944-Oct 1944 (Box 53, Folder 23)
      - Workmen's Circle, Nov 1944 (Box 53, Folder 24)
      - Workmen's Circle, Dec 1944 (Box 53, Folder 25)
      - Workmen's Circle, 1945 (Box 53, Folder 26)
      - Yiddish Scientific Institute (YIVO), 1947 (Box 53, Folder 27)
      - Yugoslavia, 1945-1947 (Box 53, Folder 28)
      - Zionism, 1947 (Box 53, Folder 29)
      - Zygielbojm, Szmul (Arthur), 1940 (Box 53, Folder 30)
- Series V: Supplement
  - Subseries V:A: JLC Publications
    - Sub Subseries V:A:1: Periodicals (arranged chronologically within each title)
      - Facts and Opinions, Series 1, December 1941: April 1962 (complete, in Yiddish), undated (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_c4a57fb6d406efe7634d3bbaccbc5a29)
        Reel#: 157-159
      - Voice of the Unconquered, March 1943 - March/April 1949 (complete, in English), undated (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_af64c8fbf0449245c09e8184a0dfb034)
    - Sub Subseries V:A:2: Pamphlets (arranged chronologically)
      - 2nd Annual Convention of the Jewish Labor Committee, October 27, 1935, New York City (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_4b3bae1eeb2ea22849acbe43b7356cf4)
        Reel#: 160
      - The Present Jewish Situation, by B.C. Vladeck; The Jewish Labor Committee and Its Work, by B. Gebiner (1935) (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_56b32edfa07fccafc98dccadf6398bc5)
      - Three Years Anti-Nazi Boycott, by Dr. Joseph Tenenbaum (1936) (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_fcb9d02168c691035b7936baa52f5730)
      - The Solution in Poland, by J. Pat (November 3, 1937) (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_9a497373df3a978c9c3836d8fde57d3d)
      - National Convention of the Jewish Labor Committee, March 4-6, 1938 (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_fa7f11f0856679060b3e32ceee3470f2)
      - Democracy, Jews and Fascism, by Walter Citrine and B.C. Vladeck; foreword by William Green (1938?), ca.1938 (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_c4959c0b580218e9076936092ab70e05)
      - Our Present Goals[speeches and reports from the JLC National Convention] (May 1938) (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_4c892c6305fa6ab177d0202e63cba5e7)
      - In the Historic Hour: Conference of the JLC(November 9, 1939, NYC) (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_c2d6d157da9701b32ead60b424bc3f02)
      - Jewish Workers at the Height of Their Goals[JLC Convention] (January 17-19, 1941, NYC) (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_dcc3dfe38dc32e4925896589df353aa6)
      - Jews after the War[report of the first conference of the JLC Research Department] (1942) Followed by English translation and a list of research projects. (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_0d6feca1248bce149f19197431f716a7)
      - Post-war Peace Demands for the Jews. Submitted to the American Jewish Conference, August 29, 1943, NYC. (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_7c1041a3b9acb8d47bccae1621959569)
      - Struggle, Rescue, Reconstruction: Report of the Nat'l Convention, of the JLC, 18-20 December 1943 (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_96588aa2562d55c04e7e196c9d5fc405)
        Reel#: 161
      - Report: N.Y. Workmen's Circle Division of the Jewish Labor Committee and "ORT"(December 26, 1943) (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_1c72330afba6318fc20ad159357d8012)
      - From Disaster to Reconstruction: Report for the Year 1943(1944) (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_2d4937152c25fb712e88e51b35a84ec6)
      - Post-war Relief and Rehabili- tation of European Jewry: Memorandum Submitted to the Council of the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration[1944] (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_80c0fd6f37b61297ca7007f86b7f51ed)
      - Relief and Reconstruction: Struggle with Anti-Semitism[convention report, Canadian JLC] (25-26 November 1944) (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_b4e87656feb5d185018926faffd81b12)
      - The Jewish Labor Committee and the American Jewish Conference(1945?), ca.1945 (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_ca441270be00552f3a361a91e38fa673)
      - Report: N.Y. Workmen's Circle Division of the Jewish Labor Committee and "ORT" for 1945 (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_cb1ff8f4d261598f815411a6756d3205)
      - Martyrs and Heroes of the Ghettos: An Exhibition Dedicated to the Second Anniversary of the Warsaw Ghetto Uprising(1945) (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_90d265f2e1d35587e8217a7cfc8b5b35)
      - Jewish Children Back to Life, by Dr. E. Patt (1946) (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_210ed02ed649277ef23aa1f520bb2315)
  - Subseries V:B: JLC-Sponsored Research Papers (arranged alphabetically by author)
    - Antisemitism among American Labor, conducted by the Institute of Social Research, Columbia University Volume 1., undated (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_2313bb8b7f49e6b45f0c218efe0dfe82)
    - Antisemitism among American Labor, conducted by the Institute of Social Research, Columbia University Volume 2., undated (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_951289af746b9f9cb559d06f956a34cd)
      Reel#: 162
    - Antisemitism among American Labor, conducted by the Institute of Social Research, Columbia University Volume 3., undated (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_77296152094a3a00c8c6722a800974a6)
      Reel#: 163
    - Antisemitism among American Labor, conducted by the Institute of Social Research, Columbia University Volume 4., undated (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_5333db11b7b98202f8c50677749a5043)
      Reel#: 164
    - Lessons of Jewish Reconstruction in the Soviet Union (A Summation of Twenty Years of the Soviet Dictatorial Experiment), by Gregor Aronson (1942) (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_c82193925fef484b9f318a67a9bfd74f)
      Reel#: 165
    - How Was Youth Productivity Actualized in Various Countries? by Alexander Erlich (n.d.), undated (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_e7da8544b8d94b301a6fc99f4ae60d0d)
    - The Situation of Jewish Youth in Pre-war Europe. Part 1: Poland, by M. Kligsberg (n.d.), undated (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_4793e1bee69de9525ea4c28256998bdc)
    - Assistance to Jewish Child War Victims, by Dr. Emanuel Patt -1942 (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_f281ceb264b92fb8f00be81f7254d713)
    - Assistance for Refugees and Repatriated Persons, by Dr. Emanuel Patt (1943) (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_c2638b358e3b03bc7286241f937edcc8)
      Reel#: 166
    - Jews and Other Minorities in the United States, by Charles B. Sherman (1943) (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_8cbf4b7c296829d4087f7208ff549cbb)
    - Rights of Asylum (Juridical and Historical Aspects of Legis- lative Doctrine), by Mark Vishniak (n.d.), undated (Box 53A, Folder data_value_missing_f64acd7994ea431d2d3bdc17e87ebe47)
  - Subseries V:C: Addendum
    Scope and Contents note
    The following documents, Box 53B including a card-file of delegate cards to the 1934 JLC's Founding Convention, were transferred to the Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives and microfilmed after filming of the four original series covering 1934-1947 had been completed. (Arranged alphabetically by subject.)
    - Aid to Hungarians, 1945-1946 (Box 53B, Folder 1)
      Reel#: 167
    - Aid to Italy, 1944 (Box 53B, Folder 2)
    - American Labor Committee to Aid British Labor, 1941 (Box 53B, Folder 3)
    - American Federation of Democratic (Box 53B, Folder 4)
    - Asch, Sholem, [1941] (Box 53B, Folder 5)
    - Belgium, 1946 (Box 53B, Folder 6)
    - Common Cause(JLC Publication), 1947 (Box 53B, Folder 7)
    - Epstein, Lasar, 1947 (Box 53B, Folder 8)
    - Finances, 1935-1937, 1942-1943 (Box 53B, Folder 9)
    - France, 1945-1946, undated (Box 53B, Folder 10)
    - German Labor Delegation, 1942 (Box 53B, Folder 11)
    - German American Congress for Democracy, 1943 (Box 53B, Folder 12)
    - Germany, 1947 (Box 53B, Folder 13)
    - Held, Adolph, 1945 (Box 53B, Folder 14)
    - International Labor Organization, 1944 (Box 53B, Folder 15)
    - Jewish-Arab Relations in Palestine by B. Sherman, [1941] (Box 53B, Folder 16)
    - Jewish Labor Committee -- Staff, 1943-1947 (Box 53B, Folder 17)
    - Jewish Labor Relations by B. Sherman, 1945 (Box 53B, Folder 18)
    - National Conference (NYC), Nov 18, 1944-Nov 19, 1944 (Box 53B, Folder 19)
    - Panama, 1940 (Box 53B, Folder 20)
    - Poland, 1946 (Box 53B, Folder 21)
    - Report of Special Meeting of the Jewish Labor Committee, Dec 19, 1944 (Box 53B, Folder 22)
    - Roumania, 1934, 1940, 1947 (Box 53B, Folder 23)
    - Seaman, Bernard, 1944 (Box 53B, Folder 24)
    - Sweden, 1947 (Box 53B, Folder 25)
    - Switzerland, 1946-1947 (Box 53B, Folder 26)